[Music]
foreign
this is Ravi welcome back to try
sentence Tasker automation tutorial
so as you all know till now I have
published around five YouTube videos
covering the basic concepts of
tricentious Tasker 16 version
so from this session onwards so we'll
start automating the test cases and then
we'll start learning different concepts
and techniques that we are going to use
by using Tasker
so as part of that
it's very necessary to know about the
introduction to xscan so this is our
lesson six where I'm gonna introduce you
to xcan and how can you scan your system
under test by using xcan in Tosca 16.
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos
thank you
okay so what is our agenda
so by this lesson
you're gonna learn how to navigate a
scan
and then how can you use the different
x-can views and the buttons that are
available under xcan window
and also you will be able to identify
the controls by properties and by anchor
and what are all the different basic
views available in xcan and what is
Advanced View and what you can access by
using Advanced view in xscan and also
what is the purpose of select on screen
option in xcan
and also I'm gonna teach you how can you
use the condensed view of your xcap
and then how can you save the controls
to your module and how can you create
the module in task okay so I think the
identification control by using
properties and anchor that I'm going to
cover in the next session but restore
all the topics how can we navigate
through xcan what is the purpose of xcan
how can we use the xcan in Tasker in
capture in the controls that I'm gonna
teach you in this lesson now let's jump
onto the system and see
how can we navigate through xcan and
what are all the different views
available in the xcan and what are the
different buttons that we have in the
x-can hunt and how can we use them okay
so now let's jump out of the system
so uh this is my try sentence task 16
version okay so now let's see
what is this sex scan and whatever the
discussion points that have told you
let's see practically okay so this is my
module section so I have already
explained you regarding these sections
in my previous session okay so you need
to navigate to module section
and then right click on your module
parent folder
and then select scan
and you have to select the scan
application because we are testing or we
are automating an application right
select an application so this will bring
you a new window to select your
application so basically it brings you
all the applications that are opened in
your system
right so I need to scan my demo webshop
application so as I told you will be
using the demo webshop that is provided
by try centers okay I explained you
about this demo a web shop in my
previous session so I would recommend
you guys to go through this
session okay so select the application
that you would like to scan and then
click on scan
so as soon as you click on scan you will
be landing onto your xcan window
and this is your basic view of your
x-can okay
so as soon as you're landing on to the
basic VRU your x-scan right now you can
directly start adding the objects that
you would like to automate okay controls
okay let's say I want to add register
you need to just
single click on register
that will add the control to your xcan
and then login
that adds your control
and this is your basic View
okay and what is Advanced View okay if
you click on Advanced View
the difference in the basic and advanced
view is you can see the technical
properties of your
object control the technical properties
of your control can be viewed in the
advanced View
okay
and if you want to go back to basic view
again you need to click on basic error
mark
okay that takes you back to your basic
View okay let's go to Advanced view
again
and see all these technical properties
okay
and the next option is
select on screen
so select on screen is not by default
selected so you need to click on select
on screen
and now you can start adding new objects
so basically it works same as basic
view but
here you can add the objects
and then you also can see the technical
properties okay let's add
shopping cart
see I have added the shopping cart let's
add wish list
okay and if you want to
remove the select on screen
view you need to again click on select
on screen that will exit your select on
screen view
okay and then again same you can go back
to basic View
right the controls whatever I added
still it there it's there
and then let's go back to Advanced View
and if you see in the advanced view I
can see all the technical properties if
you scroll down here
under technical properties whatever the
check boxes I'm seeing here right so for
this shopping cart control this shopping
cart control is being identified by the
technical property called inner text
tag if you want to identify this element
by using class name you can check this
box okay
and one more thing is
as soon as you add any new object let's
say I want to add
let's go back to basic View
let's say I want to add Apparition shoe
as soon as you add it immediately gives
you
a notification that the selected item is
unique
okay so that's one thing and now let's
see what is condensed View
so when you click on this condensed View
the condensed view tab will go to the
right side of your screen
and it gives you
full control of your system under test
application so that means you can view
your entire application now okay this is
shortcut View and now again you can add
the
controls as it is again I can add this
control by clicking on electronics
so this is added
and if you want to go back to basic view
again
click on basic View and see if this
Electronics is added yes it's there
hope you understand
and then
save your controls so whatever the
controls that you added
this is your save button on top left
corner
as soon as you click on Save
it saves all the controls to your module
let's go back to module see the new
module called demo webshop.login has
been added and all the controls that we
are we added will be saved in this new
module called demo webshop.login
okay and
this gives you an opportunity to add
more controls let's say I forgot to add
another control called gift card I can
add again and then again click on Save
so this will update your existing module
with the new control that you added
okay
so the module
the new model it will not create a new
module it basically adds a new control
to the same module okay and then what is
finished grade so what is the difference
between save and finish okay Finish
screen see when you save the control
still remain on the screen and you can
add the new controls but if you click on
finish scan or finish screen
this will
clear all the controls from your screen
and that creates your module
see the new module with all the controls
that we added
now if you want to add another module
called for example for example some
other module other page right then you
can go back to your x-scan
start scanning your
new page or new module
okay
and this the difference is
when you click on finish screen it
removes all the controls if you click on
Save the previous controls will be on
the script okay and then you can close
your
X scan
right and let's click on scan screen
again
let's say I want to add a new module
okay here let's go back to your
Advanced View
and then
now let's see what is this highlight
selection option
okay when you click on highlight
selection so okay let me add first login
okay
sorry
let me go back to basic and then click
on login
right let's go to Advanced so if I want
to highlight this control let's say you
have a lot of controls on the page
so if you want to see what where is this
login you click on highlight selection
that will highlight
the control that will highlight the
control on your application
okay so that the advantage of your
highlight again you can simply click on
highlight and then remove highlight
okay that's the advantage of highlight
selection okay so hope I have covered
all the topics that we are supposed to
learn okay save and finish done okay so
we saw the concept okay where
so in this case right I just scanned a
new module when I'm closing this I don't
want to save you can just click on no
this will not save a new module okay
so these are all the controls that we
added as a new module okay hope you all
understand the basic concepts of
X scan so this is very important from
next sessions onwards when we start
automating our test cases we are going
to use our x-scan
to create the modules and to capture the
controls and their technical properties
so if you have any queries
please provide your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond to your
queries thank you
hope you all understand the concepts of
xcan in trycentives Tasker latest
version 60.
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
foreign
[Music]